Okay, so there was a request to go
through um the options here. So I'm
going to go through the options on this
get setup and explain them. Um so on
this screen um
I didn't want I didn't select these
because what they'll do is they'll
create a little icon on your desktop and
on your like uh launching bar um that'll
let you quickly launch the get um
interface. because we're using a graphic
interface, I typically don't want to
launch that. Um, so I didn't install
those, but if you do want to interact
exclusively through the terminal, you
maybe will want to install those. Um,
down here, um, you could enable it to
constantly check to see if there's an
update for the software forget on
Windows. Um, in my experience, the
version doesn't change all of that much.
Um, so I didn't feel like that was super
important to check. And then it said add
a git bash profile to the Windows
terminal. So the Windows terminal has
two profiles by default. It has a
PowerShell and a command prompt. Um, and
what this would allow you to do is
change from PowerShell to command prompt
to a get bash terminal. It's just
another type of terminal. Um, again, if
you're using the visual interfaces to
interact with Git, then this isn't super
important, which is why I left that one
unselected. All right. So, here I told
you that you could leave uh it was on
Vim.
Oh, there we go. I said you could leave
Vim as the default editor. What the
default editor does is when you make um
when you interact with Git on the
terminal and you type get commit, um you
need to give it a message that explains
what changes you made to the code. Um,
if you're using Visual Studio Code or
um, GitHub Desktop, they actually have a
nice editor right there that you can
type all of your messages in and hit
commit and it's a nice visual interface
to interact with it. If you were
exclusively interacting over the
terminal, then it would need to open up
an editor for you to type your message.
So, it's saying which editor would you
like to use? Vim can be difficult to use
because there's certain keyboard
shortcuts you have to use to get out of
Vim. Um, and especially if you've done
all of your development in Visual Studio
Code, um, you may not be expecting to
see the Vim interface. So, if you want
to exclusively interact over the command
line, then you will probably want to
switch this to use Visual Studio Code.
U, because I'm using a graphic user
interface, um, like Visual Studio Code's
built-in um,
version control system or GitHub
Desktop, this doesn't really matter as
much. um which is why I left it as the
default. Um but you can use Visual
Studio Code if you're going to be
interacting over the terminal. Um on
this one, we adjusted the name. Um I
think I did explain this in the last
video, but normally when Git creates um
your main version of your code, they
call that master. Um but because that
has some negative connotations um you
can in new versions of git you can
overwrite it. Um so some people like to
call their main branch or their main
version of their code development or
production or something else but one of
the ones that's pretty standard is to
call it main. So I selected that and
left that option as main. Basically, all
it does is change the name of the
version, your main version of code.
All right. And then it says, how would
you like your path environment adjusted?
So, your path environment is how Windows
knows where programs are on your
computer. So, when you doubleclick on
the Chrome icon, it needs to run some
code that someone wrote to launch your
web browser. Um, and in order to do
that, it needs to know where that code
is located. Windows uses the path
environment to figure out where
different pieces of code are located. So
this is saying we're about to install
new software. Your Windows needs to know
where it's located. How would you like
us to configure it? So if we do the
first one, then it means that we can
only interact with Git from the terminal
because Windows won't really know where
it is. Only our Git terminal will know
where it is. Um, but if you're going to
use a visual interface like Visual
Studio Code's built-in um, version
control or you're going to use GitHub
Desktop, then you're going to want to
use this second option because what it
does is it allows Windows to know where
the files to run Git are. And so then
when another program says, "Hey, I want
to use Git," Windows knows where that's
located and other programs can use it.
So selecting the first option means that
you can only use the terminal to
interact with git. Selecting the second
option means that you can use any um
software to interact with git like
GitHub desktop or visual studio code. Um
and then the last one is use git and
optional Unix tools from the command
prompt. So by default Windows has a
bunch of commands that you can run. Um
one that I usually run is I think it's
ns flush or something like that. I can't
ever remember the command, but what it
does is it clears out um cached records
on my system um so that I can test when
I've assigned a new u website URL to one
of my websites and I want to make sure
it's been applied, I'll run a command
that will refresh my windows. Um that
command is built into command prompt.
There are two types of operating systems
or two main types of operating systems.
There's the Windows type of operating
system and then there's Unix type
operating systems. They have their own
set of commands that you can run. Um,
and so if you're on a Mac or a Linux,
you can run all of these commands. Um,
and they're really nice commands and I
really like them. Um, but this last
option would overwrite some of your
pre-built Windows commands and it would
overwrite them with the commands that
are available on a Mac or Linux. Again,
because I'm not planning to use the
terminal to interact with my version
control, I won't select this option. Um,
selecting the middle option allows me to
interact with the terminal with GitHub
Desktop or any other user interface. Um,
and with Visual Studio Code, selecting
the third option will allow all of those
same things, but it will also allow me
to run commands like find or um, this
one says sort will be overwritten. But
there are a bunch of other commands on a
Linux like ls and things like that that
don't work on a Windows. Um, this would
make it so that you could run those on a
Windows. Again, I'm not planning to do
that, so I'm going to leave this option.
Okay. There's a couple ways to get your
code from like GitHub or somewhere out
on the internet where it's stored. One
of those is SSH. Um SSH um is a secure
shell. Um that's what it stands for. Um
and it's a way of using your computer to
send a message to another computer and
to securely um encrypt the files and
bring them back to your computer. So
there's a couple ways to do that and
they are giving you an option. You can
either use the SSH, open SSH that comes
with Git, or you can use an external SSH
that um
does not come with Git. So, I just
choose the option that comes with Git.
Either way, what it does is it allows
you to grab your code and your files
from somewhere else and bring them to
your computer.
Okay. The next way, and this is the way
that GitHub Desktop uses, is HTTPS. So,
similar to when you visit a website,
when you visit a website, you type on
the URL bar https/
www.google.com.
What it's saying is, I would like
something from Google. Um, please go get
that information and bring it back.
Because you added the s, it means
secure. So, it's using keys, um,
cryptographic keys to encrypt the data
between Google and you so that no one
can edit it or, uh, see what you're
browsing if they were to stand in
between you and Google and try and
intercept your messages. So, this just
allows it to be more secure and it
brings it to your computer in a more
secure manner. Um, there are two options
here. The first option is to just use
the open SSL library. So that's to use
the default keys that know where where
and who people are. The second one is to
use the native Windows secure channel.
So what this does is it allows um let's
say your company manages your laptop. It
allows them to add some special keys
that are just for your company and it'll
be able to use those to interact with
specific servers. So this is the option
I like to choose and it's also the
default. Um, okay.
When you write code on a Windows and
when you write code on a Unix system
like a Mac or a Linux, um, there are two
different ways that files end their
lines. So, when you open up Visual
Studio Code, your code goes from top to
bottom and there are um, line breaks.
So, your code is now on the next line.
In order to know where a line ends, um,
Windows injects a specific character. um
at the end to say this is the end of the
line. Make sure the new line shows up on
the next line visually. Um those line
breaks are CRLF is how it's written out.
Um on a Unix, meaning a Mac or a Linux,
it's written differently. That is it's
written as an LF. So, if you were to
directly pull code, if you were to
directly copy code from a Mac onto a
Windows without changing the line
endings, Windows wouldn't know where
each line of code ended. Um, and so what
this is saying is there is going to be a
shared place where all of my code lives.
When I get that code on my computer,
what would I like it to do? So, this
first option says I want to check it out
in Windows style. meaning when I go out
and grab the code from the internet and
bring it down onto my computer, I want
you to adjust it so that it works on
Windows. Um, and then when I send it
back, I want you to readjust it from my
Windows version into a version that um,
Unix computers can use. Um, and this is
the default. The second option is to
check out ASIS and commit with Unix
style line endings. What that means is
it'll check it out and if it already had
Windows line endings, it'll use Windows
line endings. If it had um Unix line
endings, it'll use Unix line endings,
which could maybe cause you some issues,
but when you commit, you'll commit it
back as Unix line endings, which means
that everyone will be able to access it
and it'll work as intended. Um, the last
one is you cannot change the line
endings at all. So you can pull down
Unix line endings, use them as Unix line
endings, and then send up whatever you
have. So that means if your computer
made some changes at some point to put
Windows line endings, now your file will
be a mix of Windows line endings and
Unix line endings. For cleanliness and
ease of access, we're going to do the
first option because it allows us to
work in our native Windows environments,
but still commit and have it work for
everyone.
Okay, so this one um says when you use
your default terminal emulator, meaning
when you fire up that window that shows
get bash, um which one do you want to
use? So the first one is the default and
this is the option I recommend. Um this
one is um it it's a window that can be
resized. Um you can run commands in it.
The only caveat is that if you want to
run something that's a Windows command,
you have to use some special um stuff to
do that. The other one is the Windows
default console window. So that is your
powers, not your PowerShell, your
command prompt. If you open up command
prompt, command prompt is fairly
limited. There's your computer has ways
of encoding text um into code that it
can store and handle and then it
converts it back for you to see. Um
Originally there was this um encoding
system called ASI. ASI would take the
characters on your system and it would
convert it. But in the modern day with
so many languages and so many characters
not to mention emojis and all of that um
we ran out of ways to encode in ASI and
so we created a new version of encoding
called Unicode.
So, Unicode
is supported by default in this first
version, which means that any character
that shows up on basically any screen
will be able to show up in your
terminal. If you select this one, then
you'll have to reconfigure it.
Otherwise, some of them are going to
show up as like these question mark
icons, meaning it doesn't know what type
of character it's supposed to show there
because it's using Unicode and not ASKI.
Um, so if you want the full version
where you can resize the screen, you can
scroll up and down, and you can have all
of the characters show up on screen,
then you're going to want to choose this
first version.
All right, this one says, what do you
want to be the default behavior of git
pull? So, what gitpull does is it goes
out, finds where your code is located on
the internet, pulls down that version to
your computer. if you are working on
that version, um, it's going to pull
down that version and sometimes the
version on the internet and the version
on your computer aren't going to match.
So, it's asking what do you want me to
do when they don't match. So, the first
one, fast forward or merge, attempts to
just realign your code with what was on
the internet. Um, and if it's not
possible to align your code with what's
on the internet, it wants you to merge
them um, at a point in history. The
benefit of this is you can undo that
merge if something breaks. Um only ever
fast forward says let's just see if we
can combine the code naturally. If we
can't then say we can't combine the
code. Um and then this rebase option is
if you are really really really into get
and you have a whole bunch of
experience. There are developers out
there who say the only option is to
merge. There are developers out there
who say the only option is to rebase. Um
rebase basically aligns your history
down to a single line of points.
If that's too complicated, I wouldn't
choose that option. Um I would choose
fast forward and merge. Um again, this
is the default behavior if you're
interacting with it from the terminal.
If you're using a graphic user interface
like Visual Studio Code or GitHub
Desktop, this isn't really going to be
that much of an issue for you. So I'm
going to leave the default option and
move to the next one. A git credential
manager. Git credential manager um
manages credentials for you as you are
working in Git. For example, when I
deployed a website to one of the hosting
services I used, I needed to take my
code that was stored in a git repository
on my local computer and I needed to
give it to the host computer. In order
to do that, um, I had to verify that I
actually was the developer because I
don't want just anyone pushing code to
my hosted server. And so, in order to do
that, I set up a bunch of credentials to
allow me to log in and verify that I am
who I say I am. Um, if I don't use the
Git Credential Manager, this is a lot
harder to do. The git credential manager
stores your credentials and allows you
to keep sending changes out to that
server that requires you to be uh
verified. Um so this get credential
manager very helpful. I would choose
that option. You could choose the option
not to have a credential helper.
All right. So these two options
file system caching um when a computer
runs there's two types of ways it stores
information. It stores them temporarily
in what is called RAM or memory and then
it stores them permanently on your hard
drive or your disk. So what this is
saying is can we enable file caching? So
what file caching does is it reads the
appropriate files off the disk and
stores them in memory. Memory is a lot
faster to access. So if you enable file
caching, when git is trying to access
files from your disk, it will read them
once and then store them in memory and
then it'll interact with the ones in
memory rather than reading the disk
every time. This will just drastically
speed up your system. Um,
and so yeah, that's what file caching
does is it just boosts your system
performance. So if you have enough
memory, I would definitely select this
option. Um, if you have a modern
computer, chances are you have enough
memory. Okay. And then there's this
enable symbolic links. So enable
symbolic links. What that does is it
allows you to store your files in one
location and then just store a reference
to those files in another location. So
um so that you can make changes to this
file, but anyone that needs to read the
file is actually looking over here and
then getting redirected to your original
file. I don't really need that. I don't
ever use it. So I don't have that one
selected. And then that is the last
option. and you'll click install. And
this will go through and continue on
like the installing get on Windows
video.